Guide to the Americans For Immigrant Justice Records, 1982-2020; 1982-ongoing and undated RL.00035
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Immigrants and Refugees Series, 1980-2004
  - Haitians Subseries, 1981-2011
    Subseries contains documents related primarily to issues of, and cases related to, deportation and asylum specifically within the Haitian community. Many files deal with the Haitian Boat crises of 2001 and 2002, with some focus on women and children refugees and children stranded in Haiti. Subseries also includes materials on various crises in Haiti, including the AIDs crisis and the 2011 earthquake. Files include articles, letters, asylum seeker statements, district court pleadings and briefings, documentation on hunger strikes, and court documents regarding interdiction. Included is AIJ's work on the case of Rev. Joseph Dantica.
    - After the Earthquake, 2011 (Box 17)
    - Air France, 1994 (Box 17)
    - AIDS, 1987-1992 (Box 17)
    - AIDS comment, 1987-1989 (Box 17)
    - Articles, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2001), 2001-2002, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Articles, Children stranded in Haiti, 1993, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - Articles, letters to politicians, etc., 1990-1991, 1-3 of 5 folders (Box 17)
    - Articles, letters to politicians, etc., 4-5 of 5 (Box 18)
    - Asylum seeker statements, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2001), 2002 (Box 18)
    - Attorney General, INS Commissioner, International Affairs, communication, 1994 (Box 18)
    - Case #81-1497-CIV-JE, Wilmer Luberisse and Job Dessin, 1981 (Box 18)
    - Charter flights, 1994 (Box 18)
    - Children - Haiti - reports, 1991-1992, 1995 (Box 18)
    - Clinton position paper and article, 1992 (Box 18)
    - Coast guard interdiction at sea, 2002 (Box 18)
    - Comfort Suites, 2002-2003 (Box 18)
    - Conditions in Haiti: Cauler letter, 1997 (Box 18)
    - Conference on current migration crisis, Senator Kennedy, 2003 Feb. 5 (Box 18)
    - Congressional communication, 1993 (Box 18)
    - Congressional hearings,, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2001), 2002 Oct. 1, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Congressional letters, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2001), 2001-2002 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence with U.S. Department of Justice, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2001), 2001-2002 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence - Walter Cadman, INS District Director, 1994-1995 (Box 18)
    - Different viewpoints, 2002 (Box 18)
    - Documentation, U.S. consulate in Haiti, 1996 (Box 18)
    - Discriminatory treatment, 2002-2003 (Box 18)
    - Detained Haitians, 2003 (Box 18)
    - District court briefings II, habeus memos, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - District court opinions, 1985-1987 (Box 19)
    - District court pleadings I, Arellano v. Weinberger, 1984 (Box 19)
    - District court pleadings I, 1985-1987, 1-6 of 7 folders (Box 19)
    - District court pleadings I, 1985-1987, 7 of 7 folders (Box 20)
    - District court pleadings II, 1986-1989, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - EAD's, 1993, 1995 (Box 20)
    - "Freedom for 24 Haitian women" saga, 2002 (Box 20)
    - Funding requests, 1994 (Box 20)
    - General - Dow, Mark, Haiti articles, 1994-1996 (Box 20)
    - General information, 1994 (Box 20)
    - Governor Jeb Bush statement, 2002 (Box 20)
    - Haitian asylum, 1992, 7 folders (Box 20)
    - Haitian asylum seekers, 2002 (Box 21)
    - Haitian asylum seekers, 2003, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Congressional letters, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2002), 2002-2003 (Box 21)
    - FIAC correspondence, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2002), 2003 (Box 21)
    - EOIR, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2002), 2002 (Box 21)
    - INS/Human rights organizations response to Haitian boatload, 2002 October 29 (Box 21)
    - Legal, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2002), 2002-2003 (Box 21)
    - Haitian boat refugee crisis (2002 Oct. 29) press coverage, 2002, 5 folders (Box 21)
    - Smuggling charges, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2002), 2003 (Box 22)
    - Summaries/talking points, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2001) (Box 22)
    - Talking points; backgrounder; chronology, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2002) (Box 22)
    - Urgent actions; resolutions; press releases, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2002) (Box 22)
    - Women and children, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2002) (Box 22)
    - Haitian Children Awaiting Visas: A Plea for Help, 1994
      - On file/affidavits, 1993-1997 (Box 22)
      - Amnesty International, 1993-1994 (Box 22)
      - Amnesty International for children, 1994 (Box 22)
      - The Congressional Black Caucus, 1994 (Box 22)
      - Congress person, 1993 (Box 22)
      - Closing of embassies, undated (Box 22)
      - Letters of support, 1993 (Box 22)
      - Mexico, 1994 (Box 22)
      - Newspaper articles, 1991-1994 (Box 22)
      - Policy, 1993-1994 (Box 22)
      - School board of Dade county Florida, 1994 (Box 22)
      - Students' work, 1994 (Box 22)
    - Haitians in the Dominican Republic, 1996 (Box 22)
    - Haiti informational, 1993-1999 (Box 22)
    - Haitian issues, 2002-2003 (Box 22)
    - Haitian packet attachments, 2002 (Box 23)
    - Haitian packet, 2003, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Haitian packet, Haitian boat, 2001 Dec. 3, 4 folders (Box 23)
    - Haitian Refugees: A People in Search of Hope, 2004 May 1
      - Appendix A: declarations, statements and testimony of detainees and their families and their advocates (Box 23)
      - Appendix B: articles, 1-2 of 5 (Box 23)
    - Haitian Refugees
      - Appendix B: Articles, 3-5 of 5 (Box 24)
      - Appendix C: U.S. policies, declarations, legal decisions, 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Appendix D: correspondences, press releases, etc., 5 folders (Box 24)
      - Indices, additional: affidavits and articles (Box 24)
    - Haitian Refugees
      - Missing footnotes documents (Box 25)
    - H.R. 3663: Haitian refugee fairness act, 1994 (Box 25)
    - Haitian repatriations, 2000-2001 (Box 25)
    - Haiti update, 2000 (Box 25)
    - Haitian Women of Miami - Marleine Bastien (forms, memos), 1995 (Box 25)
    - Hearing on Haitian detention/interdiction, 1989 (Box 25)
    - HIV 1994-1996 (Box 25)
    - Informal briefings before U.S. commission on civil rights, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2001), 2002 June 21 (Box 25)
    - Interdiction 1994 (Box 25)
    - Interdiction lawsuit, 1984, 3 folders (Box 25)
    - Media, 1994 (Box 25)
    - Miami-Dade commissioner's resolution, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2001), 2002 (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992-1994 (Box 25)
    - The National Coalition for Haitian Rights (NCHR), 1994, 2003 (Box 25)
    - NCHR - expenses, 1994 (Box 25)
    - NGO/local organizational support, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2001), 2002-2003 (Box 25)
    - NPR morning edition (Ernest Belisere), 1992 Feb. 11 (Box 26)
    - Oversite hearing on Haitian and Cuban immigrants, 1991 (Box 26)
    - Other, 2002 (Box 26)
    - Press conference, 2003 March 24 (Box 26)
    - Press packet, 2002, November 1 (Box 26)
    - Press releases, 1994 (Box 26)
    - Press releases, letters to politicians, etc., 2002 (Box 26)
    - Press releases, urgent actions, Haitian boat (2001), 2002 (Box 26)
    - Processing immigrant visas for Haitians in Mexico, 1988 (Box 26)
    - Questions for Haitians returned to Haiti, 2002 Aug. (Box 26)
    - Rally for children, 1993 Sept. 26 (Box 26)
    - Randall Robinson hunger strike, 1994 (Box 26)
    - Refugee Refoulment: The Forced Return of Haitians under the U.S. - Haitian Interdiction Agreement, 1990 March (Box 26)
    - Reno memo on Toboso, 1994-2002 (Box 26)
    - Sign on to American Immigrant Lawyers Association, regarding Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (IIRAIRA), 1997 (Box 26)
    - Children stranded in Haiti, sign ons for report faxes, potentials - fax list of names, 1994 (Box 26)
    - South Ridge High students, 2002 (Box 26)
    - Stepick affidavits master file, 1983-1985 (Box 26)
    - St. Thomas University Law School - Parolees, 1993-1994 (Box 26)
    - Summaries, 2003 (Box 26)
    - Children stranded in Haiti, 1993 (Box 26)
    - Supporting documents about Haiti, 2002 August (Box 26)
    - They Call Us Boat People. Producer/Director: David Plane. 57:12 minutes., 1997 (Box 97, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0007)
    - Transcript of hearing, Haitian boat refugee crisis (2001), 2002 Oct. 1 (Box 26)
    - U.S. consulate in Haiti, 1993-1994 (Box 26)
    - U.S. Department of State responses to congressional inquiries regarding Haitian refugees, 2002 (Box 26)
    - Regarding U.S. Haitian policy, 1993 (Box 26)
    - YMCA Houston, 1994 (Box 26)
    - Dantica, 2004-2006 (Box 48)
      The case of Reverend Joseph N. Dantica, the uncle of the renowned Haitian author Edwidge Danticat. She writes about her family's history and this case in a memoir entitled "Brother, I'm Dying" (2007). Joseph N. Dantica died in ICE custody at Jackson Memorial Hospital in Miami, FL due to complications from cancer after being detained at Krome. He was detained for seeking asylum despite having the legal right to enter the US on an active visa. The documents available include medical records, autopsy reports, personal records, legal documents, FIAC's case against the DHS requesting his documents through FOIA, correspondence, news articles, and other communications related to the case.
    - Dantica, 2004-2006 (Box 49)
    - Dantica, 2004-2005 (Box 82)
    - Additional Haitians documents, 1995-2017 (Box 61)
    - Additional Haitians documents, 1999-2011 (Box 64)
    - FIAC v. NSA, 2001-2005 (Box 61)
      FIAC v NSA is a Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) suit against the NSA to release any and all documents proving that Haiti is being used as a staging ground for third country nationals that may be involved in terrorist plots, in particular Pakistanis and Palestinians. This was cited by US Attorney General Ashcroft as the reason why Haitian refugees and migrants were being discriminated against.
    - Moise v Bugler, 2002 (Box 64)
      Contains legal files pertaining to a lawsuit by Haitian detainees against the INS and DOJ. On December 3, 2001 US Coast Guard intercepted a boat named Simapvivetzi, carrying Haitian refugees off the coast of South Florida near Biscayne National Park. The survivors were detained at Krome and other facilities. The case covers the lawsuit of a number of detainees who filed for asylum and were requesting to be released and were suing for discrimination, mistreatment, and abuse. Includes supporting documentation, statements by detainees and governmental officials, correspondence, and research for the case conducted by AIJ attorneys.
    - Additional Haitians documents, 1995-2011 (Box 67)
    - CABA v Christopher, 1994 (Box 79)
      CABA vs Christopher is a major lawsuit that the set precedent for Guantanamo policy and was filed on behalf of over 30,000 Cuban refugees, aka balseros, interdicted at sea and detained at Guantanamo Naval Base. The Cuban American Bar Association filed the lawsuit against the Clinton administration represented by Warren Christopher, Secretary of State. The suit cites the refugees' rights under the Cuban Adjustment Act of 1966 and the "unsanitary, deplorable and medically inadequate detention camps" at the base. Haitian Refugee Center Inc. joined the suit as an Intervenor plaintiff on behalf of the over 6,000 Haitian refugees detained at Guantanamo and the discrimination and abuse they faced compared to Cuban refugees, including unaccompained minors.
    - Letters, 2004-2008 (Box 79)
    - Sove Nou, 2002-2003 (Box 87)
      A screenplay by Kevin Sharpley related to the 2001 Haitian boat incidents.
    - Haitian Refugee Immigration Fairness Act, 2003 (Box 87)
      News articles, correspondence, and other documentation related to US representative Kendrick B. Meek's attempts to expand on the original HRIFA bill.
    - Homeland Security affect on immigrants post 9/11, 2002-2004 (Box 87)
    - Krome conditions, 2006 (Box 87)
    - Crisis in Haiti related to Aristide, 2003-2004 (Box 87)
    - Miscellaneous Haitians documents, 1998-2008 (Box 87)
      Documents related to asylum seekers and TPS status, includes reports, photos, and news articles.
    - Haitian and Cuban meetings, 2002-2007 (Box 87)
    - Vialine Jean Paul case coverage and correspondence, 2009 (Box 87)
    - OAS petition, 2004-2006 (Box 87)
  - Other Files Subseries, 1980-2009
    Files contain documents related to issues of deportation, asylum, and immigration within the US, including materials regarding the Cuban refugee population and some material regarding Eastern European refugees. Subseries particularly focuses on discrimination against female immigrants, and also gay rights in an immigrant context immigration, labor, and raids on immigrant populations. Materials primarily include case studies, articles, and court reports applicable to AIJ's work.
    - Border patrol and profiling, 2006-2009 (Box 87)
    - Canadian asylum scam, 2007 (Box 87)
      Documents related to an immigration scam in which undocumented immigrants were made to pay large fees for fraudulent asylum applications to Canada. The scammers operated under the name Jerusalem Haitian Community Centre.
    - CIV - Graham #98-1134, 1998-1999, 4 folders (Box 27)
    - COFFO v FEMA, 2004-2007 (Box 79)
      Lawsuit of the Coalition of Florida Farm Workers vs the Federal Emergency Management Agency. COFFO was suing FEMA for their policy of refusing to provide victims of natural disasters (primarily after the 2004 hurricane season) who are not "qualified aliens" with short term non-cash aid. Includes correspondence, court documents, depositions, data, and invoices related to the case.
    - Cuban detainees, 1996-1998 (Box 27)
    - Detainee accounts, 2001-2008 (Box 87)
    - Detainees with minor children frequently asked question, early 2000s (Box 87)
    - Discrimination against female immigrants, 1986-1996 (Box 27)
    - U.S. Discrimination against women, 1980-1987, 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Extension 5 to Lindemann Declaration, 1986, 1-3 of 6 (Box 27)
    - Extension 5 to Lindemann Declaration, 1986, 4 to 6 of 6 (Box 28)
    - Farmworkers, 1996-1999 (Box 28)
    - Gay rights immigration, 2000-20002 (Box 28)
    - HIV update, 1992 (Box 28)
    - Immigrant women articles, letters, studies, 1988-1994, 3 folders (Box 28)
    - Immigrant women: Cheryl's notes, 1982-1993 and undated (Box 28)
    - Immigrant women: miscellaneous booklets, articles, 1991-1995 (Box 28)
    - Immigrant women: public benefits litigation, 1988 (Box 28)
    - Immigrant women: women in farm labor population, 1988 (Box 29)
    - Indefinite detention packet, 1999 (Box 29)
    - Lettman v Reno, 1994-2000 (Box 90)
      Documents related to the suit brought forward by Jamaican immigrant Robert A. Lettman vs Janet Reno, US Attorney General in 11th Circuit of US Appeals Court. Lettman seeks damages for unlawful deportation and the mishandling of his case. Documents include research, notes, correspondence, and other cases brought against US Attorney General Reno.
    - Pembina Nation fraud, 2006-2010 (Box 87)
      Documents related to an immigration scam in which a fake Native American nation took large sums of money from undocumented immigrants promising them legal status in the US through tribal membership. The scammers operated under the name Pembina Nation Little Shell Band of North America (or Little Shell Pembina Band). They primarily targeted the Haitian community of South Florida.
    - Post 9/11 articles, 2001 (Box 87)
    - Profiles of biased FL judges, 2006-2007 (Box 87)
    - Public benefits paybacks, 1996-1998, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Raids, 1997 (Box 29)
    - Raids, 1997-1998 (Box 29)
    - Raids, file #1 - documentation, 1997 (Box 29)
    - Raids, file #2 - people/organizations already faxed, 1997 (Box 29)
    - Raids, file #3 - forms for documentation, 1997 (Box 29)
    - Raids, file #4 - raids information, 1997 (Box 29)
    - Raids, file #5 - articles and miscellaneous, 1997 (Box 29)
    - Raids articles, 1998 (Box 29)
    - Raids - women, 1998 (Box 29)
    - Refugee right of spouse and children to join, 1996 (Box 29)
    - Rositch, Irina and Hristo Sabev, 1997 (Box 29)
    - Securing Our Borders: Post 9/11 Scapegoating of Immigrants, 2005 (Box 29)
    - Selugal - workplace raids, 1997 Mar. 28 (Box 29)
    - Sugar cane workers suit, 1989, 1-2 of 4 folders (Box 29)
    - Sugar cane workers suit, 1989, 3-4 of 4 (Box 30)
    - Temporary protected status - letters, addresses, etc., 1989-1994 (Box 30)
    - Trujillo et. al. v. Reno et. al, 1998, 4 folders (Box 30)
    - General - United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), 1995-1997 (Box 30)
    - Unleash the Dream: End the Colossal Waste of Young Immigrant Talent, 2010 April (Box 30)
    - Women - asylum and gender, 1995-1999 (Box 30)
- Restricted Files Series, 1982-2003
  Materials in the Restricted Series have been pulled from the Detention, Immigrants and Refugees, and A/V series based on their potentially sensitive or confidential nature. Files include legal documents such as affidavits, correspondence with or about clients, medical records, and other statements and potential evidence. Access is restricted. Researchers must receive prior authorization from donor in order to access the material in this series. Please contact Rubenstein Research Services to request access.
  Access Restrictions
  The Restricted Files Series is restricted. Researchers must receive prior authorization from donor in order to access the material in this series. All other series are unrestricted. Please contact Rubenstein Research Services to request access.
- General Organizational Records Series, 2005-2020; 2005-ongoing
  Divided into the relevant subseries of Reports and Speeches, Correspondence, Media Coverage, and Digital Presence.
  - Correspondence Subseries, 1998-2009
    The Correspondence Subseries contains materials related to correspondence, including letters and emails between AIJ and other persons or entities both governmental and non-governmental.
    - Correspondence, 1998-2009 (Box 62)
  - Events Subseries, 2005-2011
    - Seventh Annual Awards Dinner, 2005 Mar. 9 (Box 47)
    - Tenth Anniversary Dinner, 2006, Mar. 6 (Box 47)
    - Annual Awards Dinner, 2007 Feb. 13 (Box 47)
    - Hearts for Freedom Awards Dinners, 2008 Feb. 29 (Box 47)
    - Annual Awards Dinner, 2009 Feb. 17 (Box 47)
    - Awards Dinner and Celebration, 2011 Feb. 22 (Box 47)
  - Media Coverage Subseries, 1996-2002
    The Media Coverage Subseries includings documents such as news articles, press releases, information on press conferences, and a general range of media coverage related to AIJ and their interests.
    - News, press conferences, and reporting on FIAC or AIJ, 1996-2011 (Box 80)
    - Miami New Times, Jan. 17-23, 2002 (Box 99)
      A Miami New Times newspaper from the week of January 17-23, 2002. Contains a post 9/11 profile of Shaheed Mohamed, an anti-terrorist informant that was later deported, featured on the front cover.
  - Reports and Speeches Subseries, 1989-2018
    The Reports and Speeches sub-series contains long form reports created by AIJ and related organizations on topics such as detention conditions, immigration policy, and legal services for immigrants. The sub-series also includes speeches given by AIJ staff, primarily by director Cheryl Little.
    - Miscalleanous reports and speeches, 1991-2018 (Box 60)
    - Post 9/11 report research, 1997-2005 (Box 70)
    - Research for reports, 1995-2009 (Box 71)
    - Haitian children awaiting visas, April 1994 (Box 80)
    - Haitian restavek, 2002 (Box 80)
    - Reports on minors, 2002 (Box 80)
    - Cheryl Little's speeches, 1999-2007 (Box 80)
    - Notes on the BTC report, 2012-2013 (Box 80)
    - Miscalleanous reports and speeches on the work of AIJ, 2002-2016 (Box 80)
    - OIG report on September 11 detainees treatment, 2003 (Box 87)
    - Catalog of publications from the US Commission on Civil Rights, Jan. 1995 (Box 87)
    - Police community relations from the US Commission on Civil Rights, Nov. 1989 (Box 87)
    - Transcript US House hearing on problems with detainee medical care, 2008 (Box 87)
  - Digital Presence Subseries, 2011-2020; 2011-ongoing
    - Americans for Immigrant Justice website, 2011-2020; 2011-
    - Florida Immigrant Advocacy Center website, 2011-2018
    - Americans for Immigrant Justice Facebook account, 2012-2020; 2012-
    - Americans for Immigrant Justice YouTube, 2012-2020; 2012-
    - Americans for Immigrant Justice Twitter account, 2020; 2020-
- Audiovisual Materials, 1989-2013; 49 items audio and video cassettes
  Series contains promotional/educational videos produced by or for FIAC.
  - José Humberto Herrera, His personal experiences at Krome while being detained c. 2, 1989 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0024)
  - Calls from Haitian Detainees at Krome Camp, re: forcing detainees to sign, 1990-04-15 (Box 44, Audio-cassette RL00035-CS-0009)
  - HRC 4-90 #202, 1990-04-25/1990-04-27 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0034)
  - Krome interviews, 1990-05-11 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0025)
  - From folder Oversight Hearing on Haitian and Cuban Immigration, 1991 (Box 44, Audio-cassette RL00035-MCS-0001)
  - Press Conference, Miami Religious Delegation to Guantanamo, 1991-01-02 (Box 44, Audio-cassette RL00035-CS-0007)
  - Guantanamo video notes II, Crowing Rooster Arts, Inc., 1993-04; 0:48:48 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0027, Digital-materials RL00035-SET-0001, Video-file RL00035-VHS-0027.mkv)
  - Tape: Ingrid Jose, 1994-03-24 (Box 44, Audio-cassette RL00035-CS-0008)
  - Haitian Children at Guantanamo, Video News International Footage, Miami Press Conference Broadcasts, 1995-03-31 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0022)
  - A video regarding the US Government's forcible repatriation of Guantanomo's Haitian children, 1995-05 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0035)
  - Press Conference Regarding Haitian Children at GTMO by Florida Rural Legal Services, 1995-05-22 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0017)
  - Krome Spc. Picnic for Detainees, 11:00 am to 3:30 pm, 1995-07-07 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0015)
  - UM interviews, Haiti, 1995-08-06/1995-08-13; 0:28:58 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0019, Digital-materials RL00035-SET-0001, Video-file RL00035-VHS-0019.mkv)
  - Mothers For Freedom Hunger Strike at Krome Detention Center, 1999 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0036)
  - Press Conference at Krome Detention Center, 1999-03-11 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0026)
  - Oprah Winfrey: Guantamo [sic] Children and ABC World News: Person of the Week Cheryl Little. FIAC, 1998 (Box 97, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0009)
  - Mothers For Freedom Hunger Strike At Krome Detention Center, 1999-04 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0037)
  - Help for Abused Immigrant Women and Children. Asistencia para mujeres y niños inmigrantes que son abusados. FIAC., 2000 (Box 97, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0005)
  - With Liberty and Justice for All? Florida Immigrant Advocacy Center, 2000; 1 items (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0029)
  - Krome Immigration Beyond, circa 2000 (Box 97, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0006)
  - Olgine Petit Goave Haiti for Ms. Reno, circa 2000 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0016)
  - RONALD A, Florida Rural Legal Services c. 1, circa 2000 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0020)
  - RONALD A, Florida Rural Legal Services c. 2, circa 2000 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0021)
  - Press, Haitian Children At Guantanamo, Florida Immigrant Advocacy Center, circa 2000 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0030)
  - FIAC: You Can Save a Life / FIAC: Usted Puede Salvar una Vida, circa 2000 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0032)
  - Florida Immigrant Advocacy Center, 12 minutes, circa 2000 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0023)
  - Primer Impacto Edicion Nocturna, Presos de Krome rompen el silencio Ricardo Arambarri, Miami, FL, 2000-10-19 (Box 44, Video-cassette RL00035-VHS-0018)